# Sean McCarthy

(336) 817-3773 | Morrisville, NC | sean.mccarthy703@gmail.com ( mctastic m smccarthydev



# Full Stack Web Developer

Dedicated MERN stack developer with a demonstrated history of working in the service and technology industries. Experienced in CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Material UI, Materialize, ¡Query, Express is, React.js, Node.js, Next.js, MongoDB, SQL, and Git with a fundamental understanding of object-oriented programming and agile methodology.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Teaching Assistant March 2022 Coding Bootcamp | UNC Chapel Hill

Managed team of 15 to 30 help desk agents representing a significant multinational technology company specializing in consumer electronics. Worked with operations manager and quality assurance teams to help agents improve and develop customer service and troubleshooting skills. Took calls regularly to maintain troubleshooting skills. Oversaw team with the highest customer satisfaction score over the course of one month.

- Maintained above 90% customer satisfaction score and QA score on calls.
- Routinely calibrated at 100% on strict internal evaluations.

## Supervisor Jan. 2019 – Jul. 2021 Conduent | Raleigh, NC

Managed team of 15 to 30 help desk agents representing a significant multinational technology company specializing in consumer electronics. Worked with operations manager and quality assurance teams to help agents improve and develop customer service and troubleshooting skills. Took calls regularly to maintain troubleshooting skills. Oversaw team with the highest customer satisfaction score over the course of one month.

- Maintained above 90% customer satisfaction score and QA score on calls.
- Routinely calibrated at 100% on strict internal evaluations.

## Quality Assurance Analyst Nov. 2017 – Jan. 2019 Conduent | Raleigh, NC

Performed routine quality evaluations on help desk agents, both remotely and in-person. Mentored new hires and educated them on troubleshooting technical issues, handling customers in a professional manner, and following proper business procedures. Handled a small number of incoming tickets weekly to stay up to date on troubleshooting skills.

- Supported a team of 60 outliers and assisted in raising issue resolution from below 70% to above 90%. Oversaw team with the highest customer satisfaction score over the course of one month.
- Assisted multiple agents with developing skills that reduced case handle time from 30 minutes to 15 minutes.

#### Tier II Help Desk Agent May 2016 – Nov. 2017 Conduent | Raleigh, NC

Provided Tier I and Tier II technical assistance for a Fortune 500 client to upwards of 50+ end users daily. Communicated with Engineering team to resolve complex technical issues. Maintained contact with end users to ensure issue resolution and customer satisfaction.

- Resolved 95% of issues during the first contact with the customer.
- Consistently ranked within the top 10 help desk agents out of 500 total agents.

#### **EDUCATION**

Coding Boot Camp Jul. 2021 – Jan. 2022 UNC-Chapel Hill | Professional Certificate

Acquired skills in MERN stack development, databases, API interaction, and basic computer science concepts.

# **PROJECTS**

#### Christmas Movie Workshop | https://kmwine02-project03.herokuapp.com/

Full stack React application that allows users to rate movies and save their ratings in a MongoDB database.

#### PTC Binder | https://ptc-binder.herokuapp.com/

Full stack application that allows registered users to track which Pokémon cards they have in their personal collection using an SQL database. Complete with

#### Travel Guide | https://jkohrt7.github.io/Digital Travel Guide/

Front end application utilizing 3 separate APIs which allow users to read the Wikipedia entry and view the weather for the desired region.